carpathiahost.net 2019-03-07

# Privacy Policy | QTS | Data Center, Colocation & Cloud Solutions

#### Privacy Policy

Quality Realty Trust, Inc. (QTS) is sensitive to privacy issues with respect to the use of user information provided to us over the Internet. QTS is committed to maintaining the privacy and confidentiality of the personal information that we collect. For these reasons, we are disclosing to you our practices in gathering and using information that you provide us. 

#### What Information Do We Collect and How Do We Collect It?

In general, you can visit QTS on the World Wide Web without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Our web servers collect our visitors' domain names and IP addresses, but not personal email addresses. This information is used to diagnose problems with our server, measure the number of visits and number of pages viewed, and register methods by which our site was found, and methods used for viewing our site. QTS will use this information to evaluate how you use our Web site and how we can improve the content of the site.

Our analytics tools also collect information regarding the user. Specifically, this includes screen resolution, color depth, whether or not Java and Flash are installed, browser version, operating system, and mobile device type. A summary of this information, without identification of any individual user, is sometimes shared with certain third parties when discussing browser compatibility.

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (such as their e-mail address), unique identifiers (like their names), and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level).

On the QTS Customer Portal, we may collect personal information from individuals acting on behalf of our business clients, such as name, address, email address and phone number. The QTS Customer Portal generally provides access to company level operational information with some limited display of personal contact information of those accessing the portal or submitting a help desk ticket.

We also may collect answers, questions, comments, ideas, suggestions, or the like which you send to us ("QTS Related Information") when you communicate with us through the Web site or email messages generated through the Web site.

Our Web site and the QTS services described on the Web site are not directed to children under the age of 13. We do not intentionally collect or maintain information about children under the age of 13. We also do not intentionally collect or maintain any information regarding ethnic origin, political opinions, health or medical conditions, philosophical beliefs, religious beliefs or participation or other such sensitive information. Do not provide us with such information or any information that you deem to be proprietary or confidential in nature.

#### How Do We Use Information We Collect?

Your IP address is used to help identify you to us and to gather broad demographic information.

We use contact information of individuals acting on behalf of our business clients in order to process and maintain the client's account. Such information may be displayed on the QTS Customer Portal for the client's viewing only.

When you submit information via the "contact us" link on our Web site, that information is provided to our third party service provider www.salesforce.com who provides us with Customer Relationship Management software to process your request.

We use data from our surveys to track the demographic information we receive from the survey takers and to log the user's identity. This information is not given out to third parties, except in de-personalized form for purposes of web site analytics. It is not used to send the user any unrequested correspondence. When requested by a user, QTS will contact or send materials to the user for marketing or other purposes. However, we will not make user-specific information gathered on our site available to unaffiliated organizations for commercial purposes.

We may use QTS Related Information, including your answers, questions, comments, ideas, suggestions and other such information to improve on our services, market our services to you, assist you in the use of our services and improve your experience with our products. While we will protect any of your personally-identifiable information submitted with QTS Related Information, we will be free to reproduce, use, and distribute the QTS Related Information to others without restriction, permission, or license. We also will be free to use any ideas, techniques, concepts, or know-how contained in QTS Related Information that you send us for any purpose whatsoever including, but not limited to, developing and marketing products or services incorporating such information. 

QTS also will share your information with its service providers for the purpose of operating the site and facilitating the services you request. This includes service providers we utilize for payment processing, mailing, email, technology support and other such services. We will use your information to process payments and requests for services, deliver our technology or services, communicate with you regarding orders for service and to provide access to customer-oriented areas of the Web site. 

QTS also may use your information for such purposes as contacting you to let you know about updates to the QTS Web site, this privacy policy or the legal terms applicable with respect to the Web site.

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy or sell businesses or assets. In such transactions, confidential customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. In the event of a transaction involving the sale of some or all of QTS' business, customer and site visitor information may be one of the transferred assets and may be disclosed in connection with negotiations relating to a proposed transaction. In such case, the transferred information may become subject to a different privacy policy.

QTS reserves the right to disclose your Information to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal process, to defend QTS against legal claims, or if QTS determines it is necessary to investigate or take action in connection with activities that QTS suspects are illegal, threaten the safety of any person or are in violation of this policy, our acceptable use policy or our Web site terms of use.

#### Use of Cookies

QTS may make use of an Internet tool called "cookies" in order to provide you with tailored information and for identification purposes. A cookie is a small piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return.

The QTS Web site may contain links to other sites. QTS is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites.

Due to the evolving nature of the technologies that we use and the way that we conduct business, we may amend this policy from time to time. We will post any revisions on this Web site.

#### Opt-Out of Communications

You may opt-out of disclosure of your personal data to third parties for marketing purposes, including correspondence from us for marketing purposes with respect to our services. Opt-out requests should be sent to [inforequest@qtsdatacenters.com](mailto:inforequest@qtsdatacenters.com) or write us at Privacy Opt-Out, Quality Technology Services, 12851 Foster St. Ste. 205, Overland Park, KS 66213. An opt-out request regarding communications from QTS can also be made by following the unsubscribe instructions included in any email you receive from us. You may not opt-out of disclosure of blinded analytics data.

#### EU-US Privacy Shield

QTS is self-certified by with the EU-US Privacy Shield. QTS complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. QTS has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

QTS has further committed to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please rel="noopener noreferrer" contact the EU DPAs at [EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs)](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of EU DPAs are provided at no cost to you. 

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, QTS commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals in the European Union with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact support at: [support@qtsdatacenters.com](mailto:support@qtsdatacenters.com). 

Currently, QTS does not disclose your information to any third party, without your consent. Individuals have the right to access their personal data. Individuals that would like to limit the use and disclosure of their personal data can email [support@qtsdatacenters.com](mailto:support@qtsdatacenters.com), at any time. QTS is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Under certain conditions, an individual can invoke binding arbitration. We will disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. In addition, our organization retains liability in cases of onward transfers to third parties. 

All QTS subsidiaries adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles and General Data Protection Regulation.

#### Access to Information; Contacting QTS

To keep your Personal Data accurate, current, complete or limit or delete it, please contact us at [support@qtsdatacenters.com](mailto:support@qtsdatacenters.com). Upon your request, we will take reasonable steps to update, correct, limit or delete Personal Data in our possession. 

#### Contact QTS ****

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact QTS at:

QTS

Attn: Privacy Officer

12851 Foster St.

Overland Park, KS 66213

Send Email to our Compliance team

1.877.QTS.DATA (787.3282)

#### Updates to This Privacy Policy

QTS may update this policy periodically. QTS reserves the right to modify, add or remove portions of this privacy statement at its discretion. If we decide to change this policy, we will post those changes at this site. If the changes we make to the policy are material, we also may post a notice on the QTS web page (www.qtsdatacenters.com) or, in some cases, may provide notice of the changes by e-mail. This policy was last updated on May 23, 2018.
